[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "Where is the largest hospital in the world located?",
    "options": ["Kimberly", "Soweto", "Cape Town", "Sandton"],
    "answer": "Soweto"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "True or False, Table mountain's high is deeper than Kimberly Hole's Deep",
    "options": ["True", "False"],
    "answer": "False"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "What are traffic lights called is South Africa",
    "options": ["Lights", "Machines", "Stops", "none"],
    "answer": "none"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "What was mandels cell number in prision?",
    "options": ["466", "67", "27", "none of the above"],
    "answer": "466"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "South Africa is often referred to as 'what sort of nation' which describes the country's multicultural diversity?",
    "options": [
      "Democracy",
      "Free Nation",
      "Rainbow Nation",
      "none of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "Rainbow Nation"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "South Africa accounts for 80% of the world's production of which precious metal?",
    "options": ["Gold", "Silver", "Diamond", "Platinum"],
    "answer": "Platinum"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Durban, the busiest port in South Africa, is on which ocean?",
    "options": [
      "Atlantic Ocean",
      "Indian Ocean",
      "Frank Ocean",
      "none of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "Indian Ocean"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "When did Zulu people form a powerful state under the Shaka monarch",
    "options": ["1818", "1942", "1961", "none of the above"],
    "answer": "1818"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "Which writer was the first to be awarded the Booker Prize twice?",
    "options": ["J.V Riebeck", "N.R Mandela", "S.Biko", "J.M Coetzee"],
    "answer": "J.M Coetzee"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "The First Boer War was fought from 1880 to 1881 between Britain and the South African Republic; which country was victorious?",
    "options": ["British", "The South African"],
    "answer": "The South African"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Which rocky headland in Western Cape is the geographic southern tip of Africa?",
    "options": ["Cape Town", "Madagascar", "Khayelisha", "Cape Agulhas"],
    "answer": "Cape Agulhas"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "The Kruger National Park contains the 'Big 5' of wild animals; which five animals make up this 'Big 5'?",
    "options": [
      "Lions, cheetars, rhinos, elephants and buffalos",
      "Springboks, leopards, rhinos, elephants and buffalos",
      "Lions, leopards, rhinos, Springboks and buffalos",
      "Tigers, leopards, rhinos, elephants and buffalos"
    ],
    "answer": "Lions, cheetars, rhinos, elephants and buffalos"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "True or False , South Africa is the only country in the world to have hosted the Football, Rugby and Cricket World Cups?",
    "options": ["True", "False"],
    "answer": "True"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Which South African won the Nobel Peace Prize in 1984?",
    "options": [
      "Whoopie Goldberg",
      "Desmond Tutu",
      "Nelson Mandela",
      "Steve Biko"
    ],
    "answer": "Desmond Tutu"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "Who was the leader of South Africa from 1978 to 1989?",
    "options": ["WF deKlerk", "Jan Van Portgier", "P W Borter", "P J Powers"],
    "answer": "P W Borter"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "South African black population is divided into four major ethnic groups; Name Them",
    "options": [
      "Nguni,Sotho,Shangaan-Tsonga,Venda",
      "Nguni, Tswana,Xhosa,Shangaan-Pedi",
      "Nguni,Sotho, Shangaan-Venda, Tsonga",
      "none of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "Nguni,Sotho,Shangaan-Tsonga,Venda"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Which language does the phrase Umuntu ngumuntu ngabantu originate from?",
    "options": ["Xhosa", "Swati", "Zulu", "Ndebele"],
    "answer": "Zulu"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "What does the phrase “danko” mean?",
    "options": ["Hi", "Good morning", "Thank You", "You're Welcome"],
    "answer": "Thank You"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "What South African movie won an Oscar for best foreign film?",
    "options": ["Umlazi Gangster", "Tsotsi", "Mvubu The Hippo", "Lion King"],
    "answer": "Tsotsi"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "Where and when was gold discovered before the Gold Rush?",
    "options": [
      "Transvaal farm",
      "Phalaphala Farm",
      "Bergsig Trout Farm",
      "Gnu Valley Farm"
    ],
    "answer": "Transvaal farm"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "The world largest open cast mine is found in this town/city?",
    "options": ["Durban", "Johannesburg", "Kimberly", " Worcester"],
    "answer": "Kimberly"
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "Name The biggest Game Reserve located in Mpumalanga with all the big five animals at one vicinity?",
    "options": [
      "Sabi sands",
      "Kruger National Park",
      "Kapama game reserve",
      "Aquila Game reserve"
    ],
    "answer": "Kruger National Park"
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "The biggest Taxi Interchange Rank in the continent?",
    "options": [
      "MTN Rank",
      "Baragwanath Rank",
      "Durban Taxi Rank",
      "Monty Naicker Rank"
    ],
    "answer": "MTN Rank"
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "2 Nobel Peace Prize Laureates lived in this street and it is now a well renowned heritage site..which street is it ?",
    "options": [
      "Vilakazi Street",
      "Long Street",
      "Victoria Embankmen",
      "Diagonal Street"
    ],
    "answer": "Vilakazi Street"
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "The slang word for BunnyChow?",
    "options": ["Quota", "Ndwang", "Plate", "Sphahlo"],
    "answer": "Spahlo"
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "Name the state broadcaster and one other free to air broadcaster, both I formally known as “4 Channels”?",
    "options": [
      "Yfm and Metro",
      "Soweto TV and Moja Love",
      "SABC and Etv",
      "none of the above"
    ],
    "answer": "SABC and Etv"
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "The world’s highest bunjee jumping spot is found on this structure?",
    "options": [
      "Mandela Bridge",
      "Brudge WC",
      "Moses Mabhida",
      "Soweto Towers"
    ],
    "answer": "Soweto Towers"
  }
]
